<globopt>
    <!--
    CROSSOVER OPERATORS
    -->
    <crossover name="Mulitple" id="multiple:" divider="|">
        Provide a list of crossover operators. Syntax is XX%CROSSOVER|YY%CROSSOVER|..., where XX is a number from 1-99.
        The numbers MUST add up to 100% and represent how often the following crossover operator should statistically
        be used. Be aware that this only be chosen ONCE, you can append as many different other operator as you wish.
        <option id="xover1" required="True" label="50%">&lt;CROSSOVER&gt;</option>
        <option id="xover2" required="True" label="25%">&lt;CROSSOVER&gt;</option>
        <option id="xover3" required="True" label="25%">&lt;CROSSOVER&gt;</option>
    </crossover>
    <crossover name="Mutation as Crossover" id="mutationasxover:">
        Mutates both crossing idividuals with the given mutation operator instead of crossing them.
        <option id="mut" required="True">&lt;MUTATION&gt;</option>
    </crossover>
    <crossover name="Sweden" id="sweden:">
        Cut each of the parents along a plane and produce children by mixing the resulting halves. This is a very basic
        operation that will likely produce good results in almost all geometric run types. Optional cutstyle= can be 0,
        1 or 2, which determines how the cutting plane is found. Style 0 forces it to be at z=0.0, style 1 selects it
        from a gaussian distribution across the z axis spanning the cluster and style 2 from an even distribution. Be
        aware that both crossing individuals are rotated randomly before the cutting plane is determined!
        <option id="cutstyle=" required="False">2</option>
    </crossover>
    <crossover name="Germany" id="germany:">
        A basic crossover operator that simply cuts the list of molecules of both individuals at the same point and then
        exchanges the halves (no geometric information is used here). The place to cut is determined by a gaussian
        distribution that can be controlled via gausswidth=.
        <option id="gausswidth=" required="False">0.3</option>
    </crossover>
    <crossover name="Foehr" id="foehr:">
        A basic crossover operator that exchanges only orientation information of the crossing individuals. Like in
        the germany operator, the molecules are selected by randomly cutting through the lists.
        <option id="noofcuts=" required="False">1</option>
    </crossover>
    <crossover name="Norbotten" id="norbotten:">
        This is essentially the same operator as the Sweden operator, but the clusters are not rotated completely
        randomly, but only in a specified plane (default XY, so the rotation is around Z)
        <option id="cutstyle=" required="False">2</option>
        <option id="inplane=" required="False">xy</option>
    </crossover>
    <crossover name="Portugal" id="portugal:">
        This is similar to the Germany crossover operator, however it can cut the molecule list more than once.
        <option id="noofcuts=" required="False">1</option>
    </crossover>
    <crossover name="No Crossover" id="nocrossover">
        Does nothing.
    </crossover>
    <!--
    MUTATION OPERATORS
    -->
    <mutation name="Mulitple" id="multiple:" divider="|">
        Provide a list of mutation operators. Syntax is XX%MUTATION|YY%MUTATION|..., where XX is a number from 1-99.
        The numbers MUST add up to 100% and represent how often the following mutation operator should statistically
        be used. Be aware that this only be chosen ONCE, you can append as many different other operator as you wish.
        <option id="mut1" required="True" label="50%">&lt;MUTATION&gt;</option>
        <option id="mut2" required="True" label="25%">&lt;MUTATION&gt;</option>
        <option id="mut3" required="True" label="25%">&lt;MUTATION&gt;</option>
    </mutation>
    <mutation name="Monte Carlo" id="montecarlo:">
        Randomly mutate atomic coordinates around. Acceptable options for mode= are "one", "some", "all" and
        "gaussian" for atomic displacement, as well as "molone", "molsome", "molall" and "molgaussian" for the
        respective molecular version that displace entire molecules at once.
        <option id="mode=" required="False">one</option>
        <option id="maxmove=" required="False">0.2</option>
        <option id="gaussmax=" required="False">1</option>
        <option id="gausswidth=" required="False">1.0</option>
    </mutation>
    <mutation name="Norway" id="norway:">
        Invokes a re-packing of all molecules, similar to the algorithm used for the initial pool population.
    </mutation>
    <mutation name="Exchange" id="xchangemut:">
        Randomly exchanges the positions and rotations of molecules within the individual. Acceptable options for mode=
        are "single" and "multiple".
        <option id="mode=" required="False">single</option>
        <option id="gausswidth=" required="False">0.4</option>
    </mutation>
    <mutation name="No Mutation" id="nomutation">
        Does nothing.
    </mutation>
</globopt>